César Rubén Pérez Valdés

Landline: +52 55 5770 1323 **Mobile:** +52 55 3460 0793.

E-mail: perezvaldesruben@gmail.com

LinkedIn: click here.

Kaggle portfolio: click here.

About Me

I am an IT professional passionate about the field of data analytics. I feel comfortable coding in languages such as Python, R and SQL. Also, I have solid experience using spreadsheet software and BI tools such as Microsoft Power BI. I've been working in international teams for the last 6 years, this has helped me to develop my skills to adapt to continuously changing environments and challenges.

E-Learning.

- Google Data Analytics Program.
- <u>Data Science Fundamentals with</u>
 <u>Python and SQL.</u>
- Python For Everybody.
- <u>Introduction to R</u>.
- Database Design.
- Google Analytics Essentials.
- Power BI Essentials.
- Power BI Advanced.
- Power BI: Data Modeling With DAX.
- Big Data Fundamentals.
- Probability and Statistics.

Education.

- Bachelor degree in Psychology (2010 2014), Universidad de Ecatepec.
- IT Technician (2005 2008), Colegio de Estudios Científicos y Tecnológicos del Estado de México (CECyTEM) Plantel Ecatepec 1.

Work Experience.

- Coderhouse.
- Time lapse:: October, 2022 to present.
- Position: Tutor.
- About the role: Helping students of the company's IT programs to further develop new skills by providing feedback and guidance on their projects.
- Integon Service Co.
- Time lapse: May, 2022 to Present.
- Position: Data Analyst.
- About the role: Automate ETL processes, automate report creation, reconcile data between different sources.
- Achievements: Contribute to create a solid and reliable system capable of automating accounting reports.
- Quadient (GMC Software). CSM Organization.
- Time lapse: May, 2019 to February, 2022.
- Position: Software Support Analyst.
- About the role: Resolve in a timely manner system issues affecting our customers CCM solutions, these problems were mostly related to: databases, networks, algorithms, etc.
- Achievements: Become main POC for cases related to the company's cloud solution. During this time, I had the chance to build Power BI dashboards useful for the management team.

